HECTOR RAFAEL SANCHEZ DIAZ

Date of birth: 19/Dec/1989

Mobile: +49 1578 0988753

Skype: sdhector21

Linkedin: linkedin.com/in/sdhector

Email: hector.rafael.sanchez.diaz@gmail.com

Website: sdhector.github.io

Address: Schweidnitzerstraße 40, 40231, Düsseldorf.



PERSONAL STATEMENT

My experience has centered on using research techniques for tackling Management and Marketing related questions. This allows me to translate regular questions into research questions, sketch models to test a hypothesis using available data, or by designing a survey or quasi-experiment. I've worked with teams of very different people, both as a member and a leader. This has taught me important interpersonal skills, and how to negotiate effectively.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Senior Market Intelligence Analyst, Claro Dominican Republic (Telecom)

2012 - 2015

Update monthly marketing KPIs, implement the appropriate research methodology to satisfy the internal client's information needs, and participate on a number of projects like:

- Churn Prediction: Used a Logit model to estimate the likelihood, or risk, of a customer canceling their contract, and used the predictors preemptively retain potential churning customers.
- Marketing Mix Modelling: Developed a Time Series model to forecast sales as a function of control variables (i.e. Advertising Expenditure) and environmental variables (i.e. GDP growth).
- Brand Equity Measurement: Used Choice-Based Conjoint Analysis to estimate the contribution of attributes like brand, price, minutes, or gigabytes of data to the purchasing decision, in order to determine how much more are customers willing to pay for a specific brand.
- Optimal Store location model: identified the optimal distribution of the company's stores and used
 it to identify areas with too many, as this generated unwanted competition among them.
- Satisfaction indices and weather: We examined if a noisy variable such as weather was predictive of CS Indices, which would indicate these were not to be trusted without proper handling.
- KPI's Dashboard development: We used the company's BI platform to automate many reports being presented in Power Point and Excel.

Market Research Analyst, Freelance

2014 - 2017

My responsibilities can be generalized as follows:

- Devising the methodology to best tackle the client's questions.
- Design the questionnaire, or other data gathering method.
- Analyze the gathered data and make a report of the findings.

Market Research Analyst, Dichter and Neira Research Network, Dominican Republic 2011 – 2012

EDUCATION

Master of Science, Economics

University of Konstanz, Germany.

August, 2017

Postgraduate Diploma, Statistics Applied to Business

Instituto Tecnológico de Santo Domingo (INTEC), Dominican Republic.

May, 2014

Bachelor's degree, Marketing.

Pontificia Universidad Católica Madre y Maestra (PUCMM), Dominican Republic.

November, 2011

SOFTWARE TOOLS AND PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES

Microsoft Office

SPSS

RStudio

SAS Enterprise Guide

GRETL

RMarkdown

SAS Miner

JMulti

German:

RShiny

SQL

MATLAB

LANGUAGES

Spanish: Native

TOEFL 107/120 English:

A2

REFERENCES

Arturo Méndez Gómez

Market Intelligence Manager Claro Dominican Republic

+1 809 769 1515

arturointernova@gmail.com

Dayany Calixto

Intern

CAPEX Controlling. +49 1573 6784437

dayanycalixtooliveira@gmail.com

Vanessa Méndez Chavez

CEO

Lupa Research Group

+1 809 849 4612

vanessa@lupard.com

vmendezch@gmail.com

Haydis Rosario

Commercial Director

Quali Global

+1 829 574-6429

haydis.rosario@qualiglobal.com

haydisrs@gmail.com